DAVID KONTROVITZ

dkontro.dk@gmail.com

I am a software engineer with experience developing web based applications through their full design life cycle. I'm searching for a position that allows me to create applications which are easy for customers to use and enhance their lives.

SKILLS & QUALIFICATIONS

- Full stack web application development following agile methodologies
- Experience deploying applications on cloud platforms such as AWS
- Extensive experience with database design, both relational and NoSQL

TECHNOLOGIES

- Languages JavaScript, TypeScript, Node, Python, SQL
- Databases MongoDB, Postgres, Oracle
- Backend Express, Flask, PM2, Mongoose, Gulp, Swagger
- Frontend HTML5, CSS, React, Redux, Webpack, Styled Components
- Other Git, AWS, Docker, Nginx, Sequelize, GraphQL, Winston, Sentry, Redis, Mocha, Jest, Remix, MaterialUI, Web Sockets, React Native

WORK HISTORY

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | PRATT & WHITNEY

2018-Present

- Design, develop, and deploy a web application to track workflow for engine component repair procedure qualification.
- Design, develop, and deploy a web application to visualize repair procedure and tooling dependencies to aid in priority planning.
- Deploy and manage relational and NoSQL databases for apps and services.
- Develop and deploy API services for use across the company.
- Code master for several projects: review and approve pull requests.
- Gather requirements from users for new and existing applications.

DEVELOPER & DATA ANALYST | PRATT & WHITNEY

2012-2018

- Developed automated tools to analyze and assess risk associated with jet engine sales and maintenance plans.
- Developed SQL views, macros, stored procedures for use in analysis tool suite.
- Standardized modules for financial analysis and risk assessment.
- Coordinated with QA team to create test plans prior to release.
- Gathered requirements from users for new and existing tools.

TECHNICAL ANALYST | PRATT & WHITNEY

2011-2012

- Supported jet engine sales campaigns and existing contract restructures; worked on team that closed a deal with over \$250 million (NPV) in sales.
- Supported quarterly tasks to re-baseline existing maintenance contract financial metrics.
- Generated customer specific fleet maintenance forecasts and analyzed associated risk.
- Created language for new engine sales contracts and contract restructures.

PROJECT ENGINEER | PRATT & WHITNEY

2008-2011

- Managed jet engine part design tasks to improve performance and manufacturability; reported weekly task status to Program office.
- Developed business cases for jet engine part cost reduction projects: created cost/benefit analysis, developed schedule, estimated budget.
- Managed selection process of cost reduction projects based on NPV analysis and risk weighting.
- Managed all turbine test activity; coordinated activities of multiple part teams; disseminated engine part teams' test requirements to Test Engineers.
- Coordinated team trips to USAF bases for engine inspection to ascertain part performance; presented results to USAF representative personnel.

TURBINE DURABILITY ENGINEER | PRATT & WHITNEY 2002-2008

- Designed gas turbine airfoil internal cooling passages and external surface film cooling to optimize metal temperatures for F135 and other engines.
- Calculated service life of gas turbine airfoils based on failure modes and mission parameters.
- Inspected engine run hardware to gauge effectiveness of cooling scheme design and expand computational models' empirical database.
- Developed Engineering Standard Work for cooling scheme design workflow.

EDUCATION

- RENSSELAER POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE AT HARTFORD, Hartford, CT Master of Business Administration (MBA), 2009
- LOUISIANA STATE UNIVERSITY, Baton Rouge, LA
 Master of Science in Mechanical Engineering, 2002
- LOUISIANA STATE UNIVERSITY, Baton Rouge, LA Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering, 2000

PATENTS

- Airfoil With Supplemental Cooling Channel Adjacent Leading Edge; Cunha, Frank J.; Pietraszkiewicz Edward F.; Kontrovitz, David M.; Levine, Jeffrey R.; Chon, Young; Mongillo, Dominic; Teller, Bret; US 7,478,994 B2; January 20, 2009.
- Turbine Blade Trailing Edge Construction; Downs, James P.; Pietraszkiewicz, Edward; Kontrovitz, David Michael; Fukuda, Takao; US 7,371,048 B2; May 13, 2008.